Parbhat Puri

Kurukshetra - 136 128 - India https://parbhatpuri.com • https://github.com/parbhat

SUMMARY

I'm a Full Stack Web Developer with an emphasis on performance, best practices and testing in order to create better applications. My experience primarily lies with the use of the Django (a Python web framework) as well as a wide range of other tools.

I like to involve in everything from the overall direction of a project, to design, user experience, and the actual implementation. I enjoy working on open source projects as it helps to give back to the community. I'm passionate about crafting great user experiences and this influences all of my decisions as I work on a project.

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Freelance Software Developer

June 2016 - Present

- Started as a part-time freelance developer but now work full time as a freelancer. Worked on several web projects as a freelance developer for international clients. Mostly work with Python, Django, JavaScript, Sass to solve real world problems.
- - The below position turned into Software Developer where I am more involved in every aspect of the project. Most of the work includes working with Python/Django, CSS/Sass, AngularJS and contributing to open source projects.
- Full Stack Developer Intern, ChrisDev Limited, Trinidad & Tobago

April 2015 - May 2016

- Remote position performed in the summer break and 4th year of my college.
- Designing and Developing client projects using technologies Python, Django, AngularJS, Sass, etc.
- Upgraded existing projects to latest version of Django.
- Created RESTful APIs using Django Rest Framework.
- Created Test Suites which include unit tests and functional tests with Selenium. Increased test coverage of some projects to 100%.
- Started new open source projects and contributing to existing open source projects of the company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python backend development: Django, Flask, Wagtail (CMS)

Frontend development: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, AngularJS, Foundation for sites and apps, Bootstrap

Design & UX: Gimp, Pen + Paper, Sketch

Databases: MySql, PostgreSQL

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java

Operating System: GNU/Linux, macOS
Version Control: Git, mercurial

OPEN SOURCE

- Django Pandas
 - Upgraded the library to Django 1.8
 - Increased Test coverage to 93%.
- Wagtail Cookiecutter Foundation
 - Started the project from scratch and created various apps like Photo gallery, Feeds, Documents gallery, blog, etc.

- Integrated Foundation for sites 6 framework with an option to customize using Sass variables.
- Functional testing with Selenium.
- Created Makefile for easy setup of development environment.
- Written extensive documentation.
- Created grunt tasks for Image Compression and integrated Browser Sync for browser testing.

• Django Pandas examples

- Started the project from scratch and created iPython/Jupyter Notebooks that Illustrate the use of django-pandas.
- Developed a script to move selected data from csv file to database being used in django project.
- Documentation to setup project locally.

· Django Wagtail Feeds

- Initially developed the app in Wagtail Cookiecutter Foundation and then moved to a separate project.
- Created unit tests.

• Django Foundation formtags

- Upgraded to the latest Zurb Foundation for sites 6 framework.
- Created unit tests with a test coverage of 100%.

PROJECTS

• Cookiecutter Django Foundation

Cookiecutter Django Foundation is fork of awesome Cookiecutter Django. This project combines the Cookiecutter Django with the Foundation 6 frontend framework. The project contains a *settings.scss* file to easily customize the default styling of the Foundation framework.

• Python Pedia

Python Pedia is one stop solution for Python Programming language resources. The resources are categorized according to the application of language. The project is open source and has 280+ stargazers on Github. It's all about Python.

• Pelican Blue

Pelican-Blue is a responsive theme for Pelican Static Site Generator, Powered by Python Programming language. The theme has features like Mobile friendly, Syntax highlighting for code blocks, RSS/ATOM feeds and integration with Disqus and Google Analytics. The documentation of the project can be read on Github.

echildcare (SMS application)

echildcare is an SMS application which can process messages. The project has features like user registration through SMS, admin panel to check registrations, send bulk messages, create events for medicines/vaccinations. The technologies used are Django, RapidSMS, Celery, Redis. Celery is used to schedule periodic events. The detailed documentation is present on Github.

SocialNetX

SocialNetX is aimed to give users deep insights about their life by collecting data from different social networks like twitter, google plus, etc. The project consists of two parts. The first being to create a Web App with features like authenticating and authorizing users, collecting data from different social networks using their API, generating graphs, etc. Second part is to create a Rest API for Sentiment Analysis of user's data. The web app uses the Rest API to perform Sentiment Analysis on user's data.

• TechHunt - An Online Quiz Platform

TechHunt is an online Quiz platform. I used Django (Python Web Framework) for backend and Twitter Bootstrap for frontend. The authenticated users can take quizzes and view their progress. The questions can be Multiple Choice, True/False and essay type.

• Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Customer Relationship Management (CRM) Software made with Swing, JDBC, MySql. The software provides functions like login, sell, add products, track details and maintain customer records, etc. The source code is hosted on Github.

· University events websites

Created and managed websites for various events organised by the University. This includes Software Freedom Day, All India Philosophy Conference, Vikalp - A Students' Initiative, Cultural (Resurgence) and Technical (Titiksha) festivals which involves frontend and backend Development.

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016 B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

SHRI MATA VAISHNO DEVI UNIVERSITY, Jammu

CGPA: 7.53

2012 CBSE XII Examination , TAGORE PUBLIC SCHOOL, KURUKSHETRA

PERCENTAGE: 89.8%

2010 CBSE X Examination , TAGORE PUBLIC SCHOOL, KURUKSHETRA

CGPA: 9/10

CERTIFICATIONS

December 2014 CS50x, Introduction to Computer Science

edX, Harvard University, Certificate ID Number - c7231f175e354755b8de46c98dc23fae

July 2014 Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms

NPTEL, IIT Madras, Roll No: NPTEL140300004517

October 2013 Networked Life

Coursera, University of Pennsylvania

July 2013 An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python

Coursera, Rice University

ACHIEVEMENTS & POSITIONS HELD

• CBSE Merit Scholarship: Central Sector Scheme of Scholarship for College and University students (CSSS-2012).

- Speaker for Github Workshop in Software Freedom Day 2015. The Workshop covers git version control system(VCS) and git workflow to contribute to an Open Source project on github.
- Coordinated Software Freedom Day 2015 and was responsible to manage the overall event.
- Speaker for Python Workshop in Software Freedom Day 2014. The Workshop covers basics and importance of Python Programming language.
- Coordinated Software Freedom Day 2014 in my University.
- Initiated a Technical environment in the University by forming clubs like *Codechef campus chapter*, *PyClub* and organising various Workshops.

PERSONAL DATA

ADDRESS: Kurukshetra, 136 128, Haryana, India

PHONE: +91 9468315914 SKYPE: parbhat.puri

EMAIL: me@parbhatpuri.com WEBSITE: https://parbhatpuri.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/parbhat

GITHUB: https://github.com/parbhat
TWITTER: https://twitter.com/parbhatpuri
SLIDES: http://slides.com/parbhat